<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cards>
    <card>
        <id>001</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Memory Game</name>
        <description>Make the game pieces, then play with your friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers or paints</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Use your ruler and pencil to draw 16 equal squares on the cardboard. Cut out all the squares.</step>
            <step>Divide the squares up into eight sets of two squares. Draw an identical picture on each of the eight sets. For example draw a spaceship on two squares, a moon on two other squares, etc.</step>
            <step>When all the pictures are complete, mix up the pieces and place them face-down on your playing surface.</step>
            <step>Each player will turn over two squares at a time. If the pictures on your squares match, keep them and turn over two more squares. If the cards don't match turn them face-down again and let your friend take a turn. The person with the most matched squares wins the game!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>002</id>
        <month>December</month>
        <name>3-D Snowflakes</name>
        <description>Create a winter wonderland with these fun-to-make paper flakes.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>8½x11" (A4) colored paper</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Paper clips</item>
            <item>String</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Fold the paper in half so that the two long sides match up. Unfold the paper and cut along the creased line. You should now have two 4¼x11" (11x28cm) strips of paper.</step>
            <step>With one of the paper strips, start from the short edge and fold back and forth every ¾" (2cm), like a fan.</step>
            <step>Gently, fold the fanned paper in half to make a crease in the middle.</step>
            <step>Place a staple in the middle of the paper along the center crease. Your paper will look like a bow tie.</step>
            <step>Use your pencil to draw a few small triangles or half circles along the folded edges of you paper. With scissors, cut out these simple shapes. Be sure not to cut all the way across the folded paper. Snip the corners off to round out your flake.</step>
            <step>Carefully open the paper on both sides of the staple. Glue the edges together to create a round snowflake. You can use paper clips to hold the paper together while the glue dries.</step>
            <step>After the glue has dried, remove the paper clips and tie a string through one of the holes of the snowflake. Hang your snowflake from a window sill or in you bedroom.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>003</id>
        <month>September</month>
        <name>Spinning Tops</name>
        <description>Make these colorful tops and watch them spin.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Round object for tracing (canned food or jar lid)</item>
            <item>Short pencil, with a point</item>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers or crayons</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With your pencil, outline your round object on the cardboard.</step>
            <step>Carefully cut the circle out with your scissors.</step>
            <step>Use your Markers or crayons to draw a funky pattern on the cardboard circle.</step>
            <step>Locate the center point of the circle and gently push the pencil tip through the cardboard.</step>
            <step>Place a piece of paper under your top, so that you don't get pencil Markings on you tabletop. Then, gently spin your top and watch it go!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>004</id>
        <month>October</month>
        <name>Piggy Bank</name>
        <description>Save your coins in this friendly bank.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Plastic milk container (washed and dried)</item>
            <item>Egg carton</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Acrylic paint</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Pipe cleaner</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut out four of the egg cups from the bottom of the egg carton. Position your milk carton so that the handle is facing up. Glue the four egg cups to the bottom of the carton to create legs for your pig. Set it aside to dry.</step>
            <step>Next, paint the entire pig. After the paint has dried, add eyes and nostrils with your Markers.</step>
            <step>For the ears, cut two triangles from the construction paper and glue them to your pig. Then, wrap the pipe cleaner around your finger a few times to create a coil.</step>
            <step>Finally, ask an adult to cut a coin slit in the top and a small hole in the back. Poke one end of your pipe cleaner into the hole for a tail.</step>
            <step>Start saving your coins!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>005</id>
        <month>June</month>
        <name>Pressed Flower Cards</name>
        <description>Collect some flowers on your next nature walk.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Fresh flowers or leaves</item>
            <item>Tissue paper</item>
            <item>Heave book</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Pick some fresh flowers or leaves.</step>
            <step>Carefully place a flower between two pieces of tissue paper. Lay the flower as flat as possible.</step>
            <step>Place the flower and tissue paper in between the pages of a thick book. (If you are pressing several flowers, make sure to separate them from each other with several pages of your book.</step>
            <step>Leave the flowers in the book to dry for about two weeks.</step>
            <step>When the blooms are completely dry, carefully remove them from between the tissue paper. Apply them to your construction paper with a very thin layer of glue. Give this car to a friend.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>006</id>
        <month>June</month>
        <name>Recycled Bird Feeder</name>
        <description>Use an empty egg carton to feed your feathered friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Empty egg carton</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>String</item>
            <item>Birdseed</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut the lid of your egg carton off.</step>
            <step>Punch a hole in each of the four corners of the sectioned portion of the carton.</step>
            <step>Cut four equal pieces of string, approximately 18" (46cm) long. Tie on piece of string to each corner hole of the carton.</step>
            <step>Carefully, gather the ends of the four strings and knot them together, keeping the carton as level as possible.</step>
            <step>Fill the sections of the carton with birdseed and hang your feeder outside. Watch all of the birds flock to the new feeder.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>007</id>
        <month>March</month>
        <name>Bunny Ears</name>
        <description>Celebrate Easter in style.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>White poster board</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers of crayons</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Cotton ball</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut a strip of poster board approximately 2x24: (5x60cm).</step>
            <step>Have an adult help you wrap the strip around your head and secure with a stapler in the back.</step>
            <step>Cut out two long, bunny ear shapes. Color the inside of each ear pink.</step>
            <step>Glue the bunny ears to the inside of the back of the headband, near the staples.</step>
            <step>Finally, glue a cotton ball to the back of the headband, covering the staples. Slide your bunny ears on after the glue has dried.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>008</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Party Hat</name>
        <description>Why buy a party hat, when you can make your own?</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Large piece of poster board (approximately 12x18" (30x45cm))</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>String or ribbon</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Curl your poster board into a large cone shape. Overlap the edges of your cone and staple them together to secure.</step>
            <step>Trim the excess poster board from the bottom to create an even, straight edge.</step>
            <step>Cut your construction paper to approximately 3x5" (8x13cm). Create fringe by cutting several slits along the long edge of the paper, leaving about an inch (3cm) of the other long edge uncut.</step>
            <step>Carefully wrap the uncut edge of the fringe paper around the point of the hat and glue it in place. Gently fold the fringe pieces down to create more texture.</step>
            <step>Punch one hole on either side of the hat near the bottom. Cut two 12" (30 cm) pieces of ribbon inside the hat. Repeat on the other side.</step>
            <step>Decorate your hat with Markers.</step>
            <step>Get the party started by placing the hat on your head and trying the ribbon in a nice bow below your chin.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>009</id>
        <month>July</month>
        <name>Sidewalk Chalk Bull's Eye</name>
        <description>Practice your aim by yourself or compete against your friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Sidewalk chalk (3 colors)</item>
            <item>Bean Bags</item>
            <item>Sidewalk or driveway</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Draw a bull's eye with your sidewalk chalk. Use one color for the center circle, another color for the middle circle and a third color for the outside circle.</step>
            <step>Take several steps back and try your best to toss a bean bag into the center circle.</step>
            <step>If you play with a friend, take turns tossing from the same spot. For a greater challenge, take a few more steps back. Good luck!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>010</id>
        <month>November</month>
        <name>Pasta Jewelry</name>
        <description>String dry pasta to make colorful costume jewelry.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Dried pasta shapes that have holes (Macaroni, Penne, Wagon Wheels, etc.)</item>
            <item>Paper cups</item>
            <item>Food coloring</item>
            <item>White vinegar</item>
            <item>Water</item>
            <item>Paper towels or newspapers</item>
            <item>Slotted spoon or fork</item>
            <item>Yarn or dental floss</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Pour ¼ cup of vinegar and ¼ cup of water into a paper cup. Add about 10 drops of food coloring and swish around to mix.</step>
            <step>Drop a handful of pasta into the solution, making sure all the noodles are completely submerged.</step>
            <step>Let the pasta soak for 10 minutes or so, then remove it with a slotted spoon and place it on paper towels or newspapers to dry and harden overnight.</step>
            <step>Repeat the process with other colors in different cups.</step>
            <step>When completely dry, string the pasta onto yarn or dental floss to make bracelets and necklaces.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>011</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Milk Carton Paddle boat</name>
        <description>Splash in the tub with this sleek, self-propelled paddle boat.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Two 1-pint milk cartons</item>
            <item>Popsicle sticks</item>
            <item>Rubber bands</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Close the top of one milk carton and staple it shut.</step>
            <step>Put two rubber bands around the carton. Put Popsicle sticks underneath the rubber bands on two opposite sides of the carton along the same edge so the ends stick out a few inches from the bottom of the carton.</step>
            <step>From a separate carton, cut two rectangles of cardboard, about 1x2" (2.5x5cm) each. Lay one of the rectangles down, and place a rubber band on top of it crosswise. Place the other rectangle on top, sandwiching the rubber band on top of it crosswise. Place the other rectangle on top, sandwiching the rubber band between the cardboard pieces. Put a staple in each of the rectangles, and on in the center (without actually touching the rubber band) to from the paddle.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>012</id>
        <month>February</month>
        <name>Hairy Pets</name>
        <description>You can be the barber for this happy hairy pet.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Paper cup</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Potting soil</item>
            <item>Small rocks</item>
            <item>Grass seeds</item>
            <item>Water</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With Markers, draw your pet's face on your cup and color it however you like.</step>
            <step>Place a handful of small rocks in the bottom of you cup, then fill it nearly to the top with soil, and sprinkle with grass seeds. Cover the seeds with about ¼ (¾cm) more soil. Add a little water.</step>
            <step>Keep your pet in the window and watch for hair growth. Add water every few days or when it becomes dry. When the grass gets long, trim it with scissors.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>013</id>
        <month>July</month>
        <name>Stars and Stripes Wind Sock</name>
        <description>Celebrate flag day with this homemade wind sock.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Construction paper (preferably blue and white)</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>Sting</item>
            <item>Streamers (preferably red and white)</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut out several stars from the white paper. Glue these stars to one side of an 11x17" (28x43cm) piece of blue construction paper. If you don't have blue paper, use Markers or crayons to decorate your paper.</step>
            <step>Create a cylinder shape by stapling the short ends of the 11x17" (28x43cm) paper together.</step>
            <step>Cut eight streamers (four red, four white to approximately 24" (60cm) each. Staple one end of each streamer to the inside of the bottom edge of the cylinder. Be sure to alternate colors: red, white, red, white, etc.</step>
            <step>Punch three holes evenly spaced around the top edge of the cylinder. Carefully tie a 12" (30cm) piece of string to each hole. Then, tie the opposite ends together.</step>
            <step>Tie 18" (46cm) string to the knot. Use this string to tie your wind sock to a tree branch outside.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>014</id>
        <month>May</month>
        <name>Big and Bigger Bubble makers</name>
        <description>Blow bigger bubbles with this big, big bubble maker.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Lid from a plastic container of cottage cheese, sour cream, or yogurt.</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Shallow dish</item>
            <item>Soap bubble solution (store-bought or homemade)</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Poke a hole in the center of the plastic lid with the point of the scissors. Ask an adult to help if necessary. Carefully cut toward the edge, but don't go all the way to the rim. Leave approximately ¼" to 1/2" (¾ to 1¼ cm) of the top surface of the lid intact around the rim, and cut away the center portion. You'll be left with a large ring.</step>
            <step>Pour bubble solution into a shallow dish that's bigger than your bubble maker. Lay the ring upside-down in the solution. Carefully pick it up and very gently swish it through the air. You'll be blowing big, beautiful bubbles, baby!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>015</id>
        <month>February</month>
        <name>Balloon Rice Balls</name>
        <description>These homemade balls are great for juggling or a game of catch.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>9 round balloons</item>
            <item>Funnel</item>
            <item>3 cups rice (uncooked)</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Inflate one balloon, without knotting the end. Hold it closed for about a minute, then deflate. This will stretch the surface of the balloon.</step>
            <step>Place the funnel into the balloon opening. Slowly pour the rice in. Use your hands to shape into a ball. With scissors, trim the thick lip of the balloon opening off.</step>
            <step>Cut off the neck of a second (deflated) balloon. Stretch the opening slightly.</step>
            <step>Fold the neck of the rice-filled balloon over, while stretching a second balloon over the ball.</step>
            <step>Repeat steps 3 and 4 with a third balloon to complete one ball. Make two more balls and try your hand at juggling.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>016</id>
        <month>March</month>
        <name>Rock Critters</name>\
        <description>Place these critters in the garden or on your desk.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Smooth rocks (washed and dried)</item>
            <item>Acrylic paint</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Make sure that your rock is completely dry before you begin painting.</step>
            <step>Use your imagination to paint a unique character. Or, create a character that you might find outside: a turtle, a ladybug, or a spider. Allow the paint to dry completely.</step>
            <step>Glue the googly eyes on to complete your garden or paperweight friend.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>017</id>
        <name>Boomerang</name>
        <month>April</month>
        <description>Toss this boomerang and watch it come back to you.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Acrylic paints or Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Measure and cut out two strips of cardboard approximately 2x12" (5x30cm) long. Round out the corners with your scissors.</step>
            <step>Place one strip over the other and line up the center points to from a "+". Staple the two pieces together at the intersection. Decorate the boomerang with paint and Markers and allow it to dry.</step>
            <step>Fold the four ends of your boomerang up, about an inch (3cm) from the edge.</step>
            <step>Find a wide-open area, outside. Hold your boomerang by one of the "arms" and flip your wrist while you release it. It should come flying back to you. Try out different throwing techniques to see what works best for you.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>018</id>
        <name>Wooden Spoon Puppets</name>
        <month>April</month>
        <description>Meet the Spooner Family, and take them to the theater.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Wooden spoons of different sizes</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Construction paper or felt</item>
            <item>Yarn</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Decide what characters you would like to have in your puppet show. Make the Spooner Family, your own family, or classic characters, like a princess and a frog, Maybe make puppets to play Little Red Riding Hood? It's up to you.</step>
            <step>Using markers, draw and color faces on the bowl of each spoon. First decide if you want the faces to be rounded out toward the audience, or scooped in ... then decorate both the front and the back of each character.</step>
            <step>If your character has hair, make it out of yarn and glue it on to the top of the spoon. It's funny if some hair hangs loose and flips around when you move the puppets.</step>
            <step>Use construction paper of felt to make other accessories, like hats, crowns, glasses, mustaches, or even caps.</step>
            <step>Invite your friends to a puppet show!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>019</id>
        <name>Cupcake Carnations</name>
        <month>June</month>
        <description>Summer lasts a little longer when you make these sweet little flowers.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Paper cupcake wrappers of different colors</item>
            <item>Green pipe cleaners</item>
            <item>Perfume</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Take a cupcake wrapper and poke a hole in the center of it with the end of a pipe cleaner.</step>
            <step>Choose a cupcake wrapper of a different color. Poke a hole in the bottom of this wrapper and thread it onto the pipe cleaner.</step>
            <step>Experiment with layering different colors and crumpling the cupcake wrappers to make the flowers take different shapes. You can use three or even four cupcake wrappers per flower.</step>
            <step>Dab or spray a little perfume on your carnations.</step>
            <step>Give them to somebody you love!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>020</id>
        <name>Cereal Necklaces</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>You won't need to pack a snack when you wear a cereal necklace.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>O-Shaped cereal</item>
            <item>String</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Measure a length of string for you necklace. Make sure it will fit over your head after you've tied a knot in it.</step>
            <step>Gently tie one piece of cereal onto the end of your string to form a stopper. Then string cereal onto your string, just like you would do with beads. You can go with one kind of cereal for a classic look, or mix a bunch of different cereals for an artsy look.</step>
            <step>Leave a couple inches of empty string at the end. Break the first piece of cereal you tied to the string, then take the two ends of string and tie them together in a double knot.</step>
            <step>Wear your necklace and always say thank you when you receive compliments on it. When you get a little bit hungry, bite off an O or two. They're not just for breakfast anymore!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>021</id>
        <name>Ribbon Place-mats</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Decorate your table with these lovely place-mats.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Ribbon in at least 2 different colors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Tape</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut an 18" (46cm) length of ribbon, lay it horizontally on the table, and tape the ends of it down. Cut ten more pieces of the same length and set aside. You may need more, depending on the width of your ribbon.</step>
            <step>Cut a series of 12" (30cm) lengths of ribbon and line them up perpendicular to the ribbon on the table. Alternate sticking them to the horizontal ribbon with a dab of glue: the first one on top, the next one on the underside, the third one on top, and so-on.</step>
            <step>Weave the remaining 18" (46cm) lengths of ribbon in and out of the 12" (30cm) ribbons, alternating starting on top and starting on the bottom.</step>
            <step>Finish by putting a dab of glue between the ribbons that overlap, all the way around the edges, and allow to dry. Pull the tape off the table and off the ribbon where you started. Enjoy lunch on your fancy new place-mat.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>022</id>
        <name>Fuzzy Buddies</name>
        <month>August</month>
        <description>We can all use more friends, and these friends are extra warm and fuzzy.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Yarn in different colors</item>
            <item>Felt in different colors</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Make a peace sign with your non-scissors-using hand, then put the two fingers that are sticking out together. Take yarn and gently wrap it around those two fingers about 75 times.</step>
            <step>Ask an adult to carefully slip the scissors between your two fingers and cut the whole bundle of yarn. It will pop off your fingers onto the table. Then, cut the yarn pieces in half and gather them into a pile.</step>
            <step>Cut a piece of yarn about 8" (20cm) long, and lay it on the table. Place your pile of short yarn pieces crosswise on the single piece of yarn. Bring the ends of the single piece up and tie them in a very tight knot, forcing the short yarn pieces into a tight bundle ... somewhat resembling a pom-pom.</step>
            <step>Give it a haircut. Use the scissors to trim the ends of the strands of yarn that are sticking out, until you get a nice round fuzz-ball.</step>
            <step>Cut a heart-shaped piece of felt a little bit bigger than your fuzz-ball, set it on the table, add a dab of glue, and set your fuzz-ball on it. Now you have made little shoes for you Fuzzy Buddy. Glue on googly eyes, and a different colored piece of yarn for a happy smile. Use felt to make hats, sunglasses, clothes, and all kinds of fuzzy accessories for your new buddy of fuzz. Then make some fuzzy friends for your first Fuzzy Buddy.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>023</id>
        <name>Potted Pinwheels</name>
        <month>July</month>
        <description>Decorate for the 4th of July with these festive pinwheels.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>6" (15cm) square of paper</item>
            <item>Markers or crayons</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Push pin</item>
            <item>Pencil with an eraser</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Start by folding your square in half diagonally. Unfold. Fold diagonally in the opposite direction. Unfold. Your paper should now have crease marks in the shape of an "X". Decorate both sides of the paper with markers or crayons.</step>
            <step>Cut slits along each crease from the corner, to approximately 1" (2.5 cm) from the center point. You should have four triangles connected at the center.</step>
            <step>Gently curl one corner up to the center point and hold in place. Repeat this curling with every other corner. Carefully insert push pin through each corner and the center point. You may need someone to help you with this step.</step>
            <step>Finally, insert the push pin into the eraser of your pencil. Now, you can poke your pencil into the dirt of a potted plant and wait for a breeze to push your pinwheel around and around.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>024</id>
        <name>Clothespin Paratroopers</name>
        <month>September</month>
        <description>Launch a platoon of paratroopers in your own backyard.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Round-headed clothespin (the type with no spring)</item>
            <item>Plastic grocery bag</item>
            <item>Thread</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut the handles off the grocery bag and cut the sides open. You want to end up with a square of plastic approximately 12" (30cm) in size. You may even be able to get two squares from one bag.</step>
            <step>Using markers, decorate your clothespin paratrooper with a face, hair and a uniform. Maybe even a mustache.</step>
            <step>Cut four 12" lengths of thread, and tightly tie the end of each thread to each of the corners of your plastic square. Tie the opposite ends of all 4 threads together in a knot.</step>
            <step>Cut another length of thread a few inches long, and tie on end around your paratrooper's neck and the other to the know where your parachute threads meet. Prepare for launch!</step>
            <step>Very loosely wind the plastic parachute around your clothespin and toss it up into the air. Your paratrooper will gently sail down and make a happy landing on the ground.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>025</id>
        <name>Fantastic Fuzzy Felt</name>
        <month>September</month>
        <description>Create ever-changing scenes straight from your imagination.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Felt in many colors</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Sturdy cardboard</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Foam brush</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Choose a dark color of felt for the background board, such as black or dark navy blue.</step>
            <step>Cut your cardboard to match the size of a full sheet of felt. Spread a thin layer of glue all over your cardboard with the foam brush and gently press the felt into place. Let it dry. You can buy a sheet of adhesive-backed felt instead ... then just peel and stick.</step>
            <step>Cut out all sorts of shapes from your other felt colors. Make most pieces less than 1" (2.5cm) in size.</step>
            <step>Once you have a whole bunch of shapes cut out, have fun arranging them all over your felt board. Create beautiful designs, creatures, houses, landscapes, flowers ... anything you want to dream up. You don't need any more glue; the fuzz on the backboard will hold the fuzzy felt shapes in place, but it's easy to pick them up and move them around. Have fuzzy felt fun!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>026</id>
        <name>Cork Horses</name>
        <month>March</month>
        <description>Make a fine filly from popped corks. Your cork horse can't trot, but he can float!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>7 corks</item>
            <item>Yarn</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Gather all your corks. Glue them together in the shape of a horse. Start by gluing the legs to the body. Then add the neck and the head. Allow the glue to dry completely.</step>
            <step>Use markers to draw eyes and a mouth on your horse. You can add a bridle and a saddle, too.</step>
            <step>Cut some yarn and glue it on to from a mane and a tail. Giddy-up!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>027</id>
        <name>Nutty Bugs</name>
        <month>October</month>
        <description>Scoot these crazy little bugs all over the place!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Walnut shells</item>
            <item>Marbles</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Felt</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Take a walnut half-shell and decorate it with markers to look like a critter. You can make a spider, ladybug, fly, or some kind of crazy looking bug that hasn't been discovered yet!</step>
            <step>Cut felt legs and glue them to the edges of the nutshell. Add some googly eyes if you'd like. Make them look real, or make them look silly, it's up to you.</step>
            <step>When you've finished decorating and the glue has had time to dry, place a marble under each shell and scoot your bugs around on a table, floor, or any smooth surface. They'll skitter all over the place!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>028</id>
        <name>Pet Pencil Holder</name>
        <month>August</month>
        <description>Make a pencil holder that looks like your favorite furry friend.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Empty soup can (washed and dried)</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Tape</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Buttons</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut a rectangular piece of construction paper. Wrap it around the can and tape to secure.</step>
            <step>Let your imagination run wild! Turn your can into a cat, dog, or anything you wish.</step>
            <step>Glue the buttons on to make eyes. Cut out construction paper for ears. Use your markers to add details.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>029</id>
        <name>Postcard Place-mat</name>
        <month>November</month>
        <description>This is a great way to use postcards that you've received.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Thin cardboard (a large cereal box works well)</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Postcards</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Contact paper</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut your cardboard to the size of a place-mat.</step>
            <step>Gather the postcards you'd like to use. Glue them to one side of the cardboard. Overlap the cards for a nice collage. Allow the glue to dry.</step>
            <step>Ask an adult to help you cover your place-mat with contact paper.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>030</id>
        <month>December</month>
        <name>New Year's Noisemakers</name>
        <description>Ring in the New Year with this homemade noisemaker.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>2 sturdy, deep paper plates</item>
            <item>A handful of dried beans or coins</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>Ribbon</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Using your Markers, decorate the bottom of both paper plates with stars, stripes, dots, or whatever you like.</step>
            <step>Turn one of the plates over and place a handful dried beans or coins on the plate.</step>
            <step>Carefully apply glue around the rim of the paper plate containing the beans or coins.</step>
            <step>Next, match the rim of the other plate to the glued edge. You can add a few staples around the edges of the two plates to reinforce the glue. Allow the glue to dry overnight.</step>
            <step>For an extra flair, punch a few holes near the edges of your noisemaker. Tie a piece of ribbon through each hole.</step>
            <step>Hold your noisemaker tightly and shake!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>031</id>
        <month>December</month>
        <name>Another New Year's Noisemaker</name>
        <description>Ring in the New Year with this homemade noisemaker.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Small plate (for tracing)</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers or paint</item>
            <item>Wooden stick (chopstick or Popsicle stick</item>
            <item>Yarn or String</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>2 Large buttons</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With your pencil and small plate trace two identical circles onto your cardboard. Cut out the two circles.</step>
            <step>Decorate one side of each circle with your markers or paints.</step>
            <step>Glue the two circles together with one end of the stick sandwiched between the two pieces of cardboard. This will be your handle. Allow the glue to dry.</step>
            <step>Cut two pieces of yarn or string that are as long as your circle is wide. Next, punch a hole on both sides of your cardboard. Tie one end of each piece of yarn to each of the holes. Then, tie a large button to the other end of each piece of yarn.</step>
            <step>Twist your handle and make some noise.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>032</id>
        <month>September</month>
        <name>Crayon Scratch-board</name>
        <directions>Begin to reveal your true artistic self, from scratch.</directions>
        <materials>
            <item>Thick white paper or card stock</item>
            <item>Crayons</item>
            <item>Paper towel</item>
            <item>Popsicle sticks and toothpicks</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With crayons, color abstract shapes of various bright colors on the paper. Cover the entire surface of your paper with crayon.</step>
            <step>Ball up a paper towel, and use it to buff the surface of your crayon-colored paper, removing any crayon crumbs and making it nice and smooth.</step>
            <step>Take a black crayon and color the entire surface of the paper, right on top of the other colors. Cover the whole surface, leaving no color showing through.</step>
            <step>Using the Popsicle sticks and toothpicks, draw an image by scratching off the black crayon and revealing the colors beneath.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>033</id>
        <month>May</month>
        <name>Floral Mother's Day Card</name>
        <description>Your mom will love this!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>6 paper muffin cups</item>
            <item>Paint</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Fold your constriction paper in half to create a card.</step>
            <step>Paint your paper muffin cups in bright floral colors. Allow the paint to dry.</step>
            <step>Flatten three of your paper muffin cups. Glue these three flattened circles to the front of your card.</step>
            <step>Glue an upright muffin cup to the center of each circle.</step>
            <step>With your markers, draw stem for each of the flowers. Write a nice note to your mom on the inside of your card.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>034</id>
        <month>May</month>
        <name>Homemade Maraca</name>
        <description>Celebrate Cinco de Mayo with this festive maraca.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>2 paper cups</item>
            <item>Handful of uncooked beans</item>
            <item>Masking tape</item>
            <item>Paints or markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Place the uncooked beans in one of the paper cups.</step>
            <step>Turn the other cup upside down on top of the first cup, and align the rims. Tape them together with a few layers of masking tape around the edges.</step>
            <step>Use paints or markers to decorate your maraca</step>
            <step>Wait for the paint to dry.</step>
            <step>SHAKE! SHAKE!! SHAKE!!!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>035</id>
        <month>March</month>
        <name>Designer Easter Eggs</name>
        <description>Add some razz-ma-tazz to your Easter eggs!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Hard-boiled eggs</item>
            <item>Commercial egg dye</item>
            <item>Rubber bands</item>
            <item>Stickers</item>
            <item>White crayon</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Carefully wrap a rubber band around an egg several times to create a funky design. Keep in mind that when you dye your egg, the area covered by the rubber band will remain white.</step>
            <step>Create a polka-dotted egg by placing small, round stickers all over the shell. Be sure that the edges of the stickers are firmly attached to the egg. Or use white crayon to design your egg. (The dye won't stick to where you make crayon marks.</step>
            <step>With the rubber bands and stickers in place, follow the instructions provided with the dye to color your eggs.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>036</id>
        <month>November</month>
        <name>Sponge Painting</name>
        <description>Painting with sponges produces neat textures.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Sponges</item>
            <item>Black marker</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Acrylic paint</item>
            <item>White paper</item>
            <item>Newspapers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With your marker, draw simple shapes onto your sponges.</step>
            <step>Cut out the shapes with scissors.</step>
            <step>Dampen the sponge and ring out any excess water.</step>
            <step>Be sure to cover your work area with newspapers. This project can be messy!</step>
            <step>Place a small amount of acrylic paint on your paper plate.</step>
            <step>Hold the sides of your damp sponge and dip your shape into the paint.</step>
            <step>Press your sponge onto the construction paper.</step>
            <step>Create an entire scene with sponge painting. The possibilities are endless!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>037</id>
        <month>November</month>
        <name>Sweet Potato Surprise</name>
        <description>Watch a sweet potato grow some roots.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Sweet potato</item>
            <item>Toothpicks</item>
            <item>Glass of water</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Stick four toothpicks evenly around the center of a sweet potato.</step>
            <step>Rest the tooth picks on the rim of a glass of water. The bottom ⅓ of the potato should be submerged in the water.</step>
            <step>Place the sweet potato and glass of a window sill or another sunny location.</step>
            <step>Within a few weeks you should see roots growing from the bottom of the potato. Be sure to check the water level often, the bottom ⅓ of the potato should always be in water.</step>
            <step>When you see sprouts growing from he top of the potato, ask an adult to help you plant the potato in some soil</step>
            <step>Don't forget to water you plant regularly as you watch it grow.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>038</id>
        <month>February</month>
        <name>Homemade Play Dough</name>
        <description>Making the dough is half the fun.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>2 cups flour</item>
            <item>¾ cup salt</item>
            <item>¾ cup hot water</item>
            <item>Food coloring</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Mix the flour and salt together in a large bowl.</step>
            <step>Separate the dough into a few separate lumps.</step>
            <step>Knead each lump on a lightly floured surface, mixing a few drop of food coloring in as you go.</step>
            <step>Have fun making crazy shapes with you play dough.</step>
            <step>Store your dough in a plastic bag or airtight container. It should last about a week.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>039</id>
        <month>December</month>
        <name>Snowman Door Hanger</name>
        <description>Let this snowman hang out in your room.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>3 round objects in different sizes, such as: canned food, jars, drinking glasses.</item>
            <item>Cardboard (preferably white)</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>String or ribbon</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Buttons</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Trace each of your three round objects twice onto the cardboard. (You'll have six circles all together).</step>
            <step>Cut out all the circles.</step>
            <step>Place one set of circles on a table, from largest to smallest. Line them up about ½" (1¼ cm) apart from each other.</step>
            <step>Place a bead of glue along the center of each circle, in a straight line.</step>
            <step>Cut approximately 18" (46 cm) of string or ribbon. Place one end of the ribbon to the bottom (largest) circle. Then lay the string on the other two circles to connect the body of your snow man. You should have extra string above the top (smallest) circle.</step>
            <step>Glue the matching cardboard circles to your snowman, sandwiching the string in place. Then, carefully glue buttons to the front of your snowman.</step>
            <step>After the glue has completely dried. Draw eyes, a nose, and a mouth with you markers.</step>
            <step>Finally, loop the end of the string and tie a knot. Your snowman is ready to hang out.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>040</id>
        <month>February</month>
        <name>Paper Beads</name>
        <description>These beads are great for making backpack ornaments or jewelry.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Colored paper</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Straw</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Dental floss</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Make a ¾" (2 cm) line on an edge of your colored paper. Then, with your pencil make a small dot 6" (15 cm) up from the middle of your ¾" (2 cm) line.</step>
            <step>Using your pencil and ruler, draw lines connecting the dot to both ends of your ¾" (2 cm) line. You should have a long, skinny triangle.</step>
            <step>Cut out the triangle. Trace it several times onto your colored paper. Cut out all the triangles.</step>
            <step>Tightly wrap one of the paper triangles around your straw until you are about an inch (3 cm) from the end point of the paper.</step>
            <step>Place a very small dab of glue on the end point of the triangle. Secure the pointed end to the rest of the rolled paper and smooth down the edges with your straw.</step>
            <step>Repeat this process to make as many beads as you'd like. String the beads onto a piece of dental floss to make a bracelet, a necklace, or a backpack ornament.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>041</id>
        <month>October</month>
        <name>Homemade Checkerboard</name>
        <description>Use your favorite colors to make your own board.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>12" (32 cm) square of cardboard</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Acrylic paints</item>
            <item>24 bottle caps or buttons (12 or one color, 12 of another color)</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With your ruler an pencil, mark each edge of your cardboard square every 1½" (4 cm). Then draw straight lines connecting the opposite edge marks to create a perfect grid.</step>
            <step>Next, paint every other box with your favorite color. Paint the remaining squares with a different color or leave them blank.</step>
            <step>Use bottle caps or buttons as your game pieces and challenge a friend to a game of checkers!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>042</id>
        <month>September</month>
        <name>Smiley-face Zipper Pull</name>
        <description>Keep your jacket zipped all the way up to show off this custom zipper pull.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>2 large paper clips</item>
            <item>Felt scraps</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut 2" (5 cm) circles of felt. Glue them together with a paper clip sandwiched in between. Leave about ¼" (¾ cm) of the end of the paper clip sticking out.</step>
            <step>Glue on googly eyes and a big happy smile made from a different color felt.</step>
            <step>Attach the other paper clip to the loop of the paper clip that is sticking out of the felt circles. Hook your zipper pull to your jacket zipper.</step>
            <step>Try making some zippy zipper pulls out of other shapes and characters, and give them to your friends.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>042</id>
        <month>February</month>
        <name>Valentine Bouquet</name>
        <description>Give these easy-to-make flowers to your valentine.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Tissue paper</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Pipe cleaners</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Measure and cut 6" x 6" (15cm x 15cm) squares of tissue paper. You'll need five squares of paper per flower.</step>
            <step>Stack five squares of tissue paper. You can use the same color or alternate colors.</step>
            <step>Fold the stack like an accordion (back and forth), with fold approximately ½" (1¼ cm) wide. You will now have a 6" x ½" (15cm x 1¼ cm) folded strip.</step>
            <step>Twist one end of a pipe cleaner around the center point of the folded strip. This will serve as the stem of your flower.</step>
            <step>To create the petals, gently separate the tissue paper by pulling each layer up and toward the center. Repeat this process to make a many flowers as you'd like for a lovely Valentine's bouquet.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>043</id>
        <month>February</month>
        <name>Pop-up Valentine</name>
        <description>Give this card to someone special.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Clear tape</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut two 1" x 11" (3cm x 28xm) strips of construction paper. Place one strip over the other and from an "L" shape and tape together.</step>
            <step>Holding the strips at the corner, fold the bottom strip over the top. Repeat with the other strip. Alternate folding until you come to the end of the strips. Place a small piece of tape to secure the ends. You should have what looks like a paper spring.</step>
            <step>Cut a heart shape (about the size of your hand) out of the construction paper.</step>
            <step>Fold an 8½" x 11" piece of paper in half to make a card. Open the card and glue one of the paper spring to the middle of the right half of the card. Glue your heart to the other end of the spring.</step>
            <step>Allow the glue to dry. Then, write a sweet Valentine message inside. Surprise a special someone with this pop-up heart card.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>044</id>
        <month>June</month>
        <name>Ball-in-Cup Game</name>
        <description>Challenge yourself with this simple game.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Paper cup</item>
            <item>Markers or paints</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>String or twine</item>
            <item>Tin foil</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Decorate the outside of your cup with a neat design.</step>
            <step>With the pencil, poke a very small hole in the center of the bottom of your paper cup.</step>
            <step>Cut an 18" (45cm) piece of string or twine. Tie several knots at one end of the string to create one large knot. Thread the other end of the string through the hole from the inside of the cup. Gently pull the string through the hole until the large knot catches.</step>
            <step>next, tie several knots at the other end of the string. Take a small piece of foil and ball it up tightly around the knot you just created. Be sure that the tin foil ball will fit into the cup.</step>
            <step>Holding the cup, try your best to flip the ball into the cup. Good luck!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>045</id>
        <month>April</month>
        <name>Paper Bag Puppets</name>
        <description>Put on a puppet show with these fun-to-make friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Paper lunch bag</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers or crayons</item>
            <item>Yarn, buttons, googly eyes, etc.</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Lay your paper bag flat on a table. Be sure that the flap (bottom of the bag) is facing up. This flap will become your puppet's face.</step>
            <step>Use your imagination to make any character you'd like: a frog, a dog, a bird, a person. The possibilities are endless!</step>
            <step>Add facial features with markers or crayons. Glue construction paper cutouts to your bag for ears or arms. Use yarn for hair. Add whatever embellishments you can find to bring your puppet to life.</step>
            <step>After the glue has dried completely, pace your hand in the opening of the bag and watch your puppet come alive!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>046</id>
        <month>August</month>
        <name>Snappy Note Holder</name>
        <description>Keep little notes and keepsakes together in a snap!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Corrugated cardboard - approximately 10" x 12" (25cm x 30xm) </item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Rubber bands</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Decorate one side of your cardboard by gluing construction paper all over it. Start by gluing one big piece for the background, then glue smaller pieces on top to make a cool design.</step>
            <step>Make about a dozen small snips at various places around the edges of your cardboard.</step>
            <step>Stretch rubber bands around your cardboard, placing them in the snips at the edges to keep them from sliding around. Put them on in angles from one snip to another, creating a crisscross of rubber bands from top to bottom and side to side, all over you decorated cardboard.</step>
            <step>Tuck notes, drawings, photos, fortune cookie fortunes, and other little paper items behind the rubber bands.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>047</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Quilled Card</name>
        <description>Create unique cars with a few coiled strips of colored paper.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Colored paper</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>First, measure and cut several thin strips of colored paper. The strips should be approximately ¼" (¾ cm) thick, and as long as you want.</step>
            <step>Get your oil started by wrapping a strip of paper around your pencil a few times. Slide the paper off of the pencil and pull the coil tight. Roll the remainder of the paper strip around the coil.</step>
            <step>With a small dab of glue, secure the end of the strip to your coil. Hold it in place until dry. You now have a round coil. Roll as many coils as necessary to create a design for your card. Create different shapes by pinching the coils in different locations.</step>
            <step>Cut a piece of color paper for you card. Turn the coils on their sides and glue them to the front of your card in any pattern you chose. You can make flowers, shamrocks, or even animals with your quilled paper.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>048</id>
        <month>June</month>
        <name>Sssuper Slithering Mobile</name>
        <description>Let this snake hang out in your room.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Thin piece of cardboard</item>
            <item>Dinner plate</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Acrylic paints</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>String</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Start by tracing a dinner plate onto the cardboard. Cut the circle out.</step>
            <step>Place your pencil point at the center of your circle, then draw a wide spiral toward the outside of your cardboard. Next, cut along the spiral line from outside, moving in. You should have coil.</step>
            <step>Lay the coil flat on your work surface to decorate. Paint your snake a bright color and add a neat design or scales. Don't' forget the eyes and a tongue. Allow the paint to dry before decorating the other side.</step>
            <step>Finally, punch a hole in the tip of the snake's tail (center portion of the coil). Thread a string through the hole and hang your new friend in your room.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>049</id>
        <month>April</month>
        <name>Mosaic Treasure Chest</name>
        <description>Keep all your favorite things in this special box. A "mosaic" is formed by piecing smaller elements together to make a picture or design.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Shoe box</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Old magazine pages</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Water</item>
            <item>Plastic cup</item>
            <item>Small paint brush</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Start by drawing a simple shape on the lid of your shoe box. A star or a heart works well.</step>
            <step>Tear out pages from an old magazine. Choose colorful pages; these colors will make your mosaic come alive. Cut the pages into strips. Then, cut the strips into small squares.</step>
            <step>In a plastic cup, combine equal parts of water and glue. Mix with your brush.</step>
            <step>Brush a thin layer of the glue solution onto a small area of your lid design. Arrange your magazine squares on the glued area following the shape of you design. Add more glue and squares until the lid is covered.</step>
            <step>Apply another light coat of the glue solution to the top of your squares. Allow the lid to dry. This is a great box to keep all your little treasures in!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>050</id>
        <month>May</month>
        <name>Box Guitar</name>
        <description>Rock out!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Tissue box</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Rubber bands</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Paper towel tube</item>
            <item>Tape</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Carefully stretch a few rubber bands around your tissue box. They should lay over the opening.</step>
            <step>Gently slide a pencil between the box and rubber bands above the oval opening.</step>
            <step>Tape the cardboard tube to the side of the box.</step>
            <step>Decorate your guitar with markers or stickers.</step>
            <step>Strum away!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>

    <!--
        <card>
            <id></id>
            <month></month>
            <name></name>
            <description></description>
            <materials>
                <item></item>
            </materials>
            <directions>
                <step></step>
            </directions>
        </card>
    -->
    <!-- Missing second sheet
            <id></id>
            <month>March</month>
            <name>St. Pat's Parade Wand</name>
            <description>Wave on the parade with this fun project.</description>
            <materials>
                <item>Thin cardboard (a cereal box works well)</item>
                <item>Pencil</item>
                <item>Scissors</item>
                <item>Green paint</item>
                <item>Green ribbon</item>
                <item>Stapler</item>
                <item>Glue</item>
                <item>Masking tape</item>
                <item>Wooden chopstick</item>
            </materials>
            <directions>
                <step>Draw three hearts of equal size on the cardboard. Cut the hearts out and glue the three points together to from a shamrock shape.</step>
                <step>Cut several pieces of ribbon. They can all be different lengths, but don't make any longer than 18" (45 cm). Gather one end of all of the ribbons and know them together. Staple the bunch to the back of your shamrock.</step>
                <step></step>
            </directions>
        </card>
     -->
</cards>
