<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cards>

    <card>
        <id>001</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Memory Game</name>
        <description>Make the game pieces, then play with your friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Marchkers or paints</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Use your ruler and pencil to draw 16 equal squares on the carboard. Cut out all the squares.</step>
            <step>Divide the squares up into eight sets of two squares. Draw an idential picture on each of the eight sets. For example draw a spaceship on two squares, a moon on two other squares, etc.</step>
            <step>When all the pictues are complete, mix up the pieces and place them face-down on your playing surface.</step>
            <step>Each player will turn over two squares at a time. If the pictures on your squares match, keep them and turn over two more squares. If the cards don't match turn them face-down again and let your friend take a turn. The person with the most matched squares wins the game!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>002</id>
        <month>December</month>
        <name>3-D Snowflakes</name>
        <description>Create a winter wonderland with these fun-to-make paper flakes.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>8½x11" (A4) colored paper</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Paper clips</item>
            <item>String</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Fold the paper in half so that the two long sides match up. Unfold the paper and cut along the creased line. You should now have two 4¼x11" (11x28cm) strips of paper.</step>
            <step>With one of the paper strips, start from the short edge and fold back and forth every ¾" (2cm), like a fan.</step>
            <step>Gently, fold the fanned paper in half to make a crease in the middle.</step>
            <step>Place a staple in the middle of the paper along the center crease. Your paper will look like a bow tie.</step>
            <step>Use your pencil to draw a few small triangles or half circles along the folded edges of you paper. With scissors, cut out these simple shapes. Be sure not to cut all the way across the foleded paper. Snip the corners off to round out your flake.</step>
            <step>Carefully open the paper on both sides of the staple. Glue the edges together to create a round snowflake. You can use paper clips to hold the paper together while the glue dries.</step>
            <step>After the glue has dried, remove the paper clips and tie a string through one of the holes of the snowflake. Hang your snowflake from a window sill or in you bedroom.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>003</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Spinning Tops</name>
        <description>Make these colorful tops and watch them spin.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Round object for tracing (canned food or jar lid)</item>
            <item>Short pencil, with a point</item>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Marchkers or craynos</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With your pencil, outline your round object on the cardboard.</step>
            <step>Carefully cut the circle out with your scissors.</step>
            <step>Use your Marchkers or crayons to draw a funky pattern on the cardboard circle.</step>
            <step>Locate the center point of the circle and gently push the pencil tip through the cardboard.</step>
            <step>Place a piece of paper under your top, so that you don't get pencil Marchkins on you tabletop. Then, gently spin your top and watch it go!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>004</id>
        <month>October</month>
        <name>Piggy Bank</name>
        <description>Save your coins in this friendly bank.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Plasitc milk container (washed and dried)</item>
            <item>Egg carton</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Acrylic paint</item>
            <item>Marchkers</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Pipe cleaner</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut out four of the egg cups from the bottom of the egg carton. Position your milk carton so that the handle is faceing up. Glue the four egg cups to the bottom of the carton to create legs for your pig. Set it aside to dry.</step>
            <step>Next, paint the entire pig. After the paint has dried, add eyes and nostrils with your Marchkers.</step>
            <step>For the ears, cut two triangles from the construction paper and glue them to your pig. Then, wrap the pipe cleaner around your finger a few times to create a coil.</step>
            <step>Finally, ask an adult to cut a coin slit in the top and a small hole in the back. Poke one end of your pipe cleaner into the hole for a tail.</step>
            <step>Start saving your coins!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>005</id>
        <month>December</month>
        <name>New Year's Noisemakers</name>
        <description>Ring in the New Year with this homemade noisemaker.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>2 sturdy, deep paper plates</item>
            <item>A handful of dried beans or coins</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Marchkers</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>Ribbon</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Using your Marchkers, decorate the bottom of both paper plates with stars, stripes, dots, or whatever you like.</step>
            <step>Turn one of the plates over and place a handful dried beans or coins on the plate.</step>
            <step>Carefully apply glue around the rim of the paper plate containing the beans or coins.</step>
            <step>Next, match the rim of the other plate to the glued edge. You can add a few staples aroudn the edges of the two plates to reinforce the glue. Allow the glue to dry overnight.</step>
            <step>For an extra flair, punch a few holes near the edges of your noisemaker. Tie a piece of ribbon through each hole.</step>
            <step>Hold your noisemaker tightly and shake!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>006</id>
        <month>June</month>
        <name>Recycled Bird Feeder</name>
        <description>Use an empty egg carton to feed your feathered friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Empty egg carton</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>String</item>
            <item>Birdseed</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut the lid of your egg carton off.</step>
            <step>Punch a hole in each of the four corners of the sectioned portion of the carton.</step>
            <step>Cut four equal pieces of string, approximately 18" (46cm) long. Tie on piece of string to each corner hole of the carton.</step>
            <step>Carefully, gather the ends of the four strings and knot them together, keeping the carton as level as possible.</step>
            <step>Fill the sectinos of the carton with birdseed and hang your feeder outside. Watch all of the birds flock to the new feeder.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>

    <card>
        <id>007</id>
        <month>March</month>
        <name>Bunny Ears</name>
        <description>Celebrate Easter in sytle.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>White poster board</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Marchkers of crayons</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Cotton ball</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut a strip of poster board approximately 2x24: (5x60cm).</step>
            <step>Have an adult helpyou wrap the strip aroudn your head and secure with a stapler in the back.</step>
            <step>Cut out two long, bunny ear shapes. Color the insdie of each ear pink.</step>
            <step>Glue the bunny ears to the inside of the back of the headband, near the staples.</step>
            <step>Finally, glue a cotton ball to the back of teh headband, covering the staples. Slide your bunny ears on after the glue has dried.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>008</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Party Hat</name>
        <description>Why buy a party hat, when you can make your own?</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Large piece of poster board (approximately 12x18" (30x45cm))</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>String or ribbon</item>
            <item>Marchkers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Curl your poster board into a large cone shape. Overlap the edges of your cone and staple them together to secure.</step>
            <step>Trim the excess poster board from the bottom to create an even, straight edge.</step>
            <step>Cut your construction paper to approximately 3x5" (8x13cm). Create fringe by cutting several slits along the long edge of the paper, leaving about an inch (3cm) of the other long edge uncut.</step>
            <step>Carefully wrap the uncut edge of the fringe paper aroudn the point of the hat and glue it in place. Gently fold the fringe pieces down to create more texture.</step>
            <step>Punch one hole on either side of the hat near the bottom. Cut two 12" (30 cm) pieces of ribbion inside the hat. Repeat on the other side.</step>
            <step>Decemberorate your hat with Marchkers.</step>
            <step>Get the party started by placing the hat on your head and trying the ribbon in a nice bow below your chin.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>

    <card>
        <id>009</id>
        <month>July</month>
        <name>Sidewalk Chalk Bull's Eye</name>
        <description>Practice your aim by yourself or compete against your friends.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Sidewalk chalk (3 colors)</item>
            <item>BeanBags</item>
            <item>Sidewalk or driveway</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Draw a bull's eye with your sidewalk chalk. Use one color for the center circle, another color for the middle circle and a third color for the outside circle.</step>
            <step>Take several steps back and try your best to toss a bean bag into the center circle.</step>
            <step>If you play with a friend, take turns tossing from the same spot. For a greater challenge, take a few more steps back. Good luck!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>

    <card>
        <id>010</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Pasta Jewlery</name>
        <description>String dry pasta to make colorful costume jewelry.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Dried pasta shapes that have holes (Macaroni, Penne, Wagon Wheels, etc.)</item>
            <item>Paper cups</item>
            <item>Food coloring</item>
            <item>White vinegar</item>
            <item>Water</item>
            <item>Paper towels or newpapers</item>
            <item>Slotted spoon or fork</item>
            <item>Yarn or dental floss</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Pour ¼ cup of vinegar and ¼ cup of water into a paper cup. Add about 10 drops of food coloring and swish around to mix.</step>
            <step>Drop a handful of pasta into the solution, making sure all the noodles are completely submerged.</step>
            <step>Let the pasta soak for 10 minutes or so, then remove it with a slotted spoon and place it on paper towels or newspapers to dry and harden overnight.</step>
            <step>Repeat the process with other colors in different cups.</step>
            <step>When completely dry, string the pasta onto yarn or dental floss to make bracelets and necklaces.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>011</id>
        <month>January</month>
        <name>Milk Carton Paddleboat</name>
        <description>Splash in the tub with this sleek, self-propelled paddleboat.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Two 1-pint milk cartons</item>
            <item>Popsicle sticks</item>
            <item>Rubber bands</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Close the top of one milk carton and staple it shut.</step>
            <step>Put two rubber bands aroudn the carton. Put Popsicle sticks underneath the rubber bands on two opposite sides of the carton along the same edge so the ends stick out a few inches from the bottom of the carton.</step>
            <step>From a separate carton, cut two rectangels of cardboard, about 1x2" (2.5x5cm) each. Lay one of the rectangles down, and place a rubber band on top of it crosswise. Place the other rectangle on top, sandwiching the rubber band on top of it crosswise. Place the other rectangle on top, sandwiching the rubber band between the cardboard pieces. Put a staple in each en fo the rectangles, and on in the center (without actually touching the rubber band) to from the paddle.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>012</id>
        <month>Febuary</month>
        <name>Hairy Pets</name>
        <description>You can be the barber for this happy hairy pet.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Paper cup</item>
            <item>Marchkers</item>
            <item>Potting soil</item>
            <item>Small rocks</item>
            <item>Grass seeds</item>
            <item>Water</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>With Marchkers, draw your pet's face on your cup and color it however you like.</step>
            <step>Place a handful of small rocks in the bottom of you cup, then fill it nearly to the top with soil, and sprinkle with grass seeds. Cover the seeds with about ¼ (¾cm) more soil. Add a little water.</step>
            <step>Keep your pet in the window and watch for hair growth. Add water every few days or when it becomes dry. When the grass gets long, trim it with scissors.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>013</id>
        <month>June</month>
        <name>Stars and Stripes Wind Sock</name>
        <description>Celebrate flag day with this homemade wind sock.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Construction paper (perferably blue and white)</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Hole punch</item>
            <item>Sting</item>
            <item>Streamers (perferably red and white)</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut out several stars from the white paper. Glue these stars to one side of an 11x17" (28x43cm) piece of blue construction paper. If you don't have blue paper, use Marchkers or crayons to decorate your paper.</step>
            <step>Create a cylinder shape by stapling the short ends of teh 11x17" (28x43cm) paper together.</step>
            <step>Cut eight streamers (four red, four whiteO to approximately 24" (60cm) each. Staple one end of each streamer to the insdie of the bottom edge of the cylinder. Be sure to alternate colors: red, white, red, white, etc.</step>
            <step>Punch three hoels evenly spaced aroudn the top edge of the cylinder. Carefully tie a 12" (30cm) piece of string to each hole. Then, tie the opposite ends together.</step>
            <step>Tie 18" (46cm) string to the knot. Use this string to tie your wind sock to a tree branch outside.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>014</id>
        <month>May</month>
        <name>Big and Bigger Bubblemakers</name>
        <description>Blow bigger bubbles with this big, big bubblemaker.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Lid from a plasitc container of cottage cheese, sour cream, or yogurt.</item>
            <item>Scisors</item>
            <item>Shallow dish</item>
            <item>Soap bubble solution (store-bought or homemade)</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Poke a hole in the center of the plastic lid with the point of the scissors. Ask an adult to help if necessary. Carefully cut toward teh edge, but don't go all the way to the rim. Leave approximately ¼" to 1/2" (¾ to 1¼ cm) of the top surface of the lid intact aroudn the rim, and cut away the center portion. You'll be left with a large ring.</step>
            <step>Pour buble solution into a shallow dish that's bigger than your bubblemaker. Lay the ring upside-down in the solution. Carefully pick it up and very gently swish it through the air. You'll be blowin' big, beautiful bubbles, baby!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>015</id>
        <month>Febuary</month>
        <name>Ballon Rice Balls</name>
        <description>These homemade balls are great for juggling or a game of catch.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>9 round balloons</item>
            <item>Funnel</item>
            <item>3 cups rice (uncooked)</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Inflate one balloon, without knotting the end. Hold it closed for about a minute, then deflate. This will stretch the surface of the balloon.</step>
            <step>Place the funnel into the balloon opening. Slowly pour the rice in. Use your hands to shape into a ball. With scissors, trim the thick lip of the balloon opening off.</step>
            <step>Cut off the neck of a second (deflated) balloon. Strecth the opening slightly.</step>
            <step>Fold the neck of the rice-filled balloon over, while stretching a second balloon over the ball.</step>
            <step>Repeat steps 3 and 4 with a third balloon to complete one ball. Make two more balls and try your hand at juggling.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>016</id>
        <month>March</month>
        <name>Rock Critters</name>\
        <description>Place these critters in the garden or on your desk.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Smooth rocks (washed and dried)</item>
            <item>Acrylic paint</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Make sure that your rock is completely dry before you beign painting.</step>
            <step>Use your imagination to paint a unique character. Or, create a character that you might find outside: a turtle, a ladybug, or a spider. Allow the paint to dry completely.</step>
            <step>Glue the googly eyes on to complete your garden or paperweight friend.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>017</id>
        <name>Boomerang</name>
        <month>April</month>
        <description>Toss this boomerang and watch it come back to you.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Cardboard</item>
            <item>Ruler</item>
            <item>Pencil</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Stapler</item>
            <item>Acrylic paints or Marchkers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Measure and cut out two strips of cardboard approximately 2x12" (5x30cm) long. Round out the corners with your scissors.</step>
            <step>Place one strip over the other and line up the center points to from a "+". Staple the two pieces together at the intersection. Decorate the boomerang with paint and Marchkers and allow it to dry.</step>
            <step>Fold the four ends of your boomerang up, about an inch (3cm) from the edge.</step>
            <step>Find a wide-open area, outside. Hold your boomerang by one of the "arms" and flip your wrist while you release it. It should come flying back to you. Try out different throwing techniques to see what works best for you.</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
    <card>
        <id>018</id>
        <name>Wooden Spoon Puppets</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Meet the Spooner Family, and take them to the theater.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Wooden spoons of different sizes</item>
            <item>Markes</item>
            <item>Construction paper of felt</item>
            <item>Yarn</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Decide what characters you would like ot have in your puppet show. Make the Spooner Family, your own family, or classic characters, like a princess and a frog, Maybe make puppets to play Little Red Riding Hood? It's up to you.</step>
            <step>Using markers, draw and color faces on the bowl of each spoon. First decide if you want the faces to be rounded out toward the audience, or scooped in ... then decorate both the front and the back of each character.</step>
            <step>If your character has hair, make it out of yarn and glue it on to the top of the spoon. It's funny if some hair hangs loose and flips around when you move the puppets.</step>
            <step>Use construction paper of felt to make other accessories, like hats, crowns, glasses, mustaches, or even caps.</step>
            <step>Invite your friends to a puppet show!</step>
        </directions>
    </card>
       <card>
        <id>019</id>
        <name>Cupcake Carnations</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Summer lasts a little longer when you make these sweet little flowers.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Paper cupcake wrappers of differnt colors</item>
            <item>Green pipe cleaners</item>
            <item>Perfume</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Take a cupcake wrapper and poke a hole in the center of it with the end of a pipe cleaner.</step>
            <step>Choose a cupcake wrapper of a different color. Poke a hole in the bottom of this wrapper and thread it onto the pipe cleaner.</step>
            <step>Experiment with layering different colors and crumpling the cupcake wrappers to make the flowers take differnt shapes. You can use three or even four cupcake wrappers per flower.</step>
            <step>Dab or spray a little perfume on your carnations.</step>
            <step>Give them to somebody you love!</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>020</id>
        <name>Cereal Necklaces</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>You won't need to pack a snack when you wear a cereal necklace.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>O-Shaped cereal</item>
            <item>String</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Measure a length of string for you necklace. Make sure it will fit over your head after you've tied a knot in it.</step>
            <step>Gently tie one piece of ceral onto the end of your string to form a stopper. Then string cereal onto your string, just like you would do with beads. You can go with one kind of cereal for a classic look, or mix a bunch of different cereals for an artsy look.</step>
            <step>Leave a couple inches of empty string at the end. Break the first piece of cereal you tied to the string, then take the two ends of string and tie them together in a double knot.</step>
            <step>Wear your necklace and always say thank you when you recieve compliments on it. When you get a little bit hungry, bite off an O or two. They're not just for breakfast anymore!</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>021</id>
        <name>Ribbon Placemats</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Decorate your table with these lovely placemats.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Ribbon in at least 2 different colors</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Tape</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut an 18" (46cm) length of ribbon, lay it horizontally on the table, and tape the ends of it down. Cut ten more pieces of the same length and set aside. You may need more, depending on the width of your ribbon.</step>
            <step>Cut a series of 12" (30cm) lengths of ribbon and line them up perpendicular to the ribbon on the table. Alternate sticking them to the horizontal ribon with a dab of glue: the first one on top, the next one on the underside, the third one on top, and so-on.</step>
            <step>Weave the remaining 18" (46cm) lengths of ribbon in and out of the 12" (30cm) ribbons, alternating starting on top and starting on the bottom.</step>
            <step>Finsih by puttin ga dab of glue between the ribbons that overlap, all the way aroudn the edges, and allow to dry. Pull the tape off the table and off the ribbon where you started. Enjoy lunch on your fancy new placemat.</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>022</id>
        <name>Fuzy Buddies</name>
        <month>August</month>
        <description>We can all use more friends, and these friends are extra warm and fuzzy.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Yarn in different colors</item>
            <item>Felt in different colors</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Make a peace sign with your non-scissors-using hand, then put the two fingers that are sticking out together. Take yarn and gently wrap it aroudn those two fingers about 75 times.</step>
            <step>Ask an adult to carefully slip the scissors between your two fingers and cut the whole bundle of yarn. It will pop off your fingers onto the table. Then, cut the yarn pieces in half and gather them into a pile.</step>
            <step>Cut a piece of yarn about 8" (20cm) ong, and lay it on the table. Place your pile of short yarn pieces crosswise on the single piece of yarn. Bring the ends of the single piece up and tie them in a very tight knot, forcing the short yarn pieces into a tight bundle ... somwhat resembling a pom pom.</step>
            <step>Give it a haircut. Use the scissors to trim the ends of the strands of yarn that are sticking out, until you get a nice round fuzzball.</step>
            <step>Cut a heart-shaped piece of felt a little bit bigger than your fuzzball, set it on the table, add a dab of glue, and set your fuzzball on it. Now you have made little shoes for you Fuzzy Buddy. Glue on googly eyes, and a different colored piece of yarn for a happy smile. Use felt to make hats, sunglasses, clothes, and all kinds of fuzzy accessories for your new buddy of fuzz. Then make some fuzzy friends for your first Fuzzy Buddy.</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>023</id>
        <name>Potted Pinwheels</name>
        <month>July</month>
        <description>Decorate for the 4th of July with these festive pinwheels.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>6" (15cm) square of paper</item>
            <item>Markers or crayons</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Push pin</item>
            <item>Pencil with an eraser</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Start by folding your square in half diagonally. Unfold. Fold diagonally in the opposite direction. Unfold. Your paper shoudl now have crease marks in the shape of an "X". Decorate both sides of the paper with markers or crayons.</step>
            <step>Cut slits along each crease from the corner, to approximately 1" (2.5 cm) from the center point. You should have four triangles connected at the center.</step>
            <step>Gently curl one corner up to the center point and hold in place. Repeat this curling with every other corner. Carefully insert pushpin through each corner and the center point. You may need someone to help you with this step.</step>
            <step>Finally, insert the pushpin into the eraser of your pencil. Now, you can poke your pencil into the dirt of a potted plant and wait for a breeze to push your pinwheel around and around.</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>024</id>
        <name>Clothespin Paratroopers</name>
        <month>September</month>
        <description>Launch a platoon of paratroopers in your own backyard.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Round-headed clothespin (the type with no spring)</item>
            <item>Plastic grocery bag</item>
            <item>Thread</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut the handles off the grocery bag and cut the sides open. You want to end up with a square of plastic approximately 12" (30cm) in size. You may even be able to get two squares from one bag.</step>
            <step>Using markers, decorate your clothespin paratrooper with a face, hair and a unifrom. Maybe even a mustache.</step>
            <step>Cut four 12" lengths of thread, and tighly tie the end of each thread to each of the corners of your plastic square. Tie the opposite ends of all 4 threads together in a knot.</step>
            <step>Cut another length of thread a few inches long, and tie on end around your paratrooper's neck and the other to the know where your parachute threads meet. Prepare for launch!</step>
            <step>Vey loosely wind the plastic parachute aroudn your clothespin and toss it up into the air. Your paratrooper will gently sail down and make a happy landing on the ground.</step>            
        </directions>
    </card> 
        <card>
        <id>025</id>
        <name>Fantastic Fuzzyfelt</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Create ever-changing scenes straight from your imagination.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Felt in many colors</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Sturdy cardboard</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Foam brush</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Choose a dark color of felt for the background board, such as black or dark navy blue.</step>
            <step>Cut your cardboard to match the size of a full sheet of felt. Spread a thin layer of glue all over your cardboard with the foam brush and gently press the felt into place. Let it dry. You can buy a sheet of adhesive-backed felt instead ... then just peel and stick.</step>
            <step>Cut out all sorts of shapes from your other felt colors. Make most pieces less than 1" (2.5cm) in size.</step>
            <step>Once you have a whole bunch of shapes cut out, have fun arranging them all over your felt board. Create beautiful designs, creatures, houses, landscapes, flowers ... anything you want to dream up. You don't need any more glue; the fuzz on the backboard will hold the fuzzy felt shapes in place, but it's easy to pick them up and move them around. Have fuzzyfelt fun!</step>            
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>026</id>
        <name>Cork Horses</name>
        <month>March</month>
        <description>Make a fine filly from popped corks. Your cork horse can't trot, but he can flaot!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>7 corks</item>
            <item>Yarn</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Gather all your corks. Glue them together in the shape of a horse. Start by gluing the legs to the body. Then add the neck and the head. Allow the glue to dry completely.</step>
            <step>Use markers to draw eyes and a mouth on your horse. You can add a bridle and a saddle, too.</step>
            <step>Cut some yarn and glue it on to from a mane and a tail. Giddy-up!</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>026</id>
        <name>Nutty Bugs</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Scoot these crazy little bugs all over the place!</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Walnut shells</item>
            <item>Marbles</item>
            <item>Googly eyes</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
            <item>Felt</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Take a walnut half-shell and decorate it with markers to look like a critter. You can make a spider, ladybug, fly, or some kind of crazy looking bug that hasn't been discovered yet!</step>
            <step>Cut felt legs and glue them to the edges of the nutshell. Add some googly eyes if you'd like. Make them look real, or make them look silly, it's up to you.</step>
            <step>When you've finished decorating and the glue has had time to dry, palce a marble under each shell and scoot your bugs around on a table, floor, or any smooth surface. They'll skitter all over the place!</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>027</id>
        <name>Pet Pencil Holder</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>Make a pencil holder that looks like your favorite furry friend.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Empty soup can (washed and dried)</item>
            <item>Construction paper</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Tape</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Buttons</item>
            <item>Markers</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut a rectangular piece of construction paper. Wrap it aroudn the can and tape to secure.</step>
            <step>Let your imagination run wild! Turn your can into a cat, dog, or anything you wish.</step>
            <step>Glue the buttons on to make eyes. Cut out construction paper for ears. Use your markers to add details.</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 
    <card>
        <id>028</id>
        <name>Postcard Placemat</name>
        <month>May</month>
        <description>This is a great way to use postcards that you've recieved.</description>
        <materials>
            <item>Thin cardboard (a large cereal box works well)</item>
            <item>Scissors</item>
            <item>Postcards</item>
            <item>Glue</item>
            <item>Contact paper</item>
        </materials>
        <directions>
            <step>Cut your cardobard to the size of a placemat.</step>
            <step>Gather the postcards you'd liek to use. Glue them to one side of the cardboard. Overlap the cards for a nice collage. Allow the glue to dry.</step>
            <step>Ask an adult to help you cover your placemat with contact paper.</step>
        </directions>
    </card> 





</cards>